# Syed Ali Hussain Bukhari

Lahore, Punjab, Pakistan 

■ 24020413@lums.edu.pk 

■ 03176640310

# **SUMMARY**

Driven by a strong research orientation, I adeptly leverage the power of data to propel my business endeavors forward. With a keen eye for detail and a deep understanding of market dynamics, I am able to introduce innovation together with profitability within the business venture.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Web Developer

**Aerotech Dynamics** 

July 2023 -October 2023, California, USA

- · Served as a Team Leader for Website Development.
- · Led and actively contributed to Website Design and Development.

# B2B Food Service Operations Management.

Independent

March 2023 - April 2023, LUMS

- · Developed and executed a marketing strategy to reach target customers, generating an approximate revenue of Rs 1 lakh in first 20 days.
- · Demonstrated strong interpersonal and customer service skills, managing relationships with suppliers, customers, and delivery partners.
- · Developed and implemented food safety and quality control standards in compliance with best practices to ensure customer satisfaction.

## **PROJECTS**

## Agricultural land transformation and its economic impacts

Assessing the Economic Impacts of Agricultural Land Transformation through Machine Learning (Current) · October 2023 - Present

- · Using satellite images to investigate the profound effects of a surge in real estate development.
- · Utilizing machine learning to process satellite imagery to assess and forecast its economic consequences.

#### **Vending Machine**

October 2022 - December 2022

- · Innovated, designed, and rebuilt the traditional tea/coffee machines after finding a gap in the market with extensively high demand.
- · Received positive feedback from stakeholders and investors, highlighting the project's potential for market success and profitability.
- · Utilized 3d printing to ensure precision in design and implemented innovative features, such as cashless payment systems and contactless serving, to enhance efficiency and customer experience. Still costing significantly less than the market price.

#### **App Development**

 $LUMS \cdot https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.mycompany.conLUMS \cdot June~2023 - August~2023 - August~20$ 

- · Initiated, designed, and completed the project independently.
- · Developed an All-Inclusive Application for the LUMS, offering features such as a marketplace, food order placement, and room services.
- $\cdot \ Committed \ to \ a \ philanthropic \ mission \ by \ directing \ the \ entire \ monthly \ revenue \ generated \ from \ the \ application \ toward \ charitable \ causes.$

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Bachelor of Science in Economics**

Minor in Mathematics, Computational Finance · Lahore University of Management Sciences · Lahore, Pakistan · 2024

#### A'leve

Lahore Grammar School • Multan • 2020

#### MEDALS AND HONORS

Dean's Honor listed

Gold Medalist - A' level & O'level

LUMS LGS · 2020

### **COURSEWORK**

Data Science/Python/Machine-learning/SQL/PowerBi.

datacamp · 2023

# **SKILLS**

C++, Python, Pandas, STATA, RATS, Power BI, Machine learning, Data cleaning, Blender, Photoshop, MS Excel, Office.